{
	"questions": [
		{
			"id": "1",
			"question": "Pre-flight Check",
			"answer": "- Inspect the drone for any visible physical damage, such as cracks or loose parts. \n- Ensure all propellers are securely attached and in good condition. \n- Check the battery level and verify that it is properly inserted. \n- Confirm that the remote controller is functioning correctly and has sufficient battery power. \n- Verify GPS signal strength and calibrate the compass if necessary. \n- Check that the firmware is up to date."
		},
		{
			"id": "2",
			"question": "Battery Care",
			"answer": "- Use only manufacturer-recommended batteries for your drone. \n- Before each flight, inspect the battery for any signs of swelling or damage. \n- Follow proper charging practices and use the manufacturer's recommended charger. \n- Avoid overcharging or fully discharging the battery to extend its lifespan. \n- Store batteries in a cool, dry place at the recommended storage charge level."
		},
		{
			"id": "3",
			"question": "Propeller Maintenance",
			"answer": "- Regularly inspect the propellers for any signs of damage, such as cracks or chips. \n- Clean the propellers after each flight to remove dirt, debris, or residue. \n- Replace any damaged or worn-out propellers promptly to ensure safe and balanced flight."
		},
		{
			"id": "4",
			"question": "Firmware Updates",
			"answer": "- Stay updated with the latest firmware releases from the drone manufacturer.\n - Before updating, carefully read and follow the manufacturer's instructions.\n - Connect your drone to a reliable internet connection and use the recommended software or app for the update process.\n - Ensure that the drone battery has sufficient charge to complete the update."
		},
		{
			"id": "5",
			"question": "Cleaning and Storage",
			"answer": " - After each flight, gently clean the drone's body, landing gear, and camera (if applicable) using a soft, lint-free cloth. \n - Avoid using harsh chemicals or solvents that may damage the drone's components. \n - Store your drone in a dry, dust-free environment, ideally in a protective case or bag. \n - If your drone is foldable, make sure to properly fold and secure it for storage."
		},
		{
			"id": "6",
			"question": "Flight Environment",
			"answer": "- Choose suitable flying locations that are free from obstacles, power lines, and other potential hazards.\n - Consider weather conditions such as strong winds, rain, or extreme temperatures before flying.\n - Avoid flying in areas with electromagnetic interference, such as near radio towers or high-voltage power lines.\n - Respect local laws and regulations regarding drone operations and obtain necessary permissions if required."
		},
		{
			"id": "7",
			"question": "Professional Servicing",
			"answer": "- If you encounter persistent issues or notice significant performance problems with your drone, consider seeking professional servicing.\n - Contact the drone manufacturer's customer support or an authorized repair center for assistance.\n - Follow any warranty guidelines provided by the manufacturer for repair or servicing."
		},
		{
			"id": "8",
			"question": "Do I need to register my drone with the authorities?",
			"answer": "Yes, drone registration is mandatory for most drone operators in the UK. As of 2020, if your drone weighs 250 grams or more, you are required to register it with the CAA and obtain an Operator ID. Additionally, if you are flying a drone under the Specific Category, you may need to register for an additional Flyer ID. It is important to familiarize yourself with the registration process and ensure compliance with the CAA's requirements."
		},
		{
			"id": "9",
			"question": "Can I fly a drone at night?",
			"answer": "In the UK, flying a drone at night is allowed under certain conditions. The CAA's regulations require the drone to have proper lighting that allows it to be seen from a distance of at least 150 meters. This ensures visibility and helps maintain safety during night flights. It's crucial to follow the specific regulations regarding night flying and ensure compliance with lighting requirements to ensure the safety of other aircraft and people on the ground."
		},
		{
			"id": "10",
			"question": "Do I need a license to fly a drone in the UK?",
			"answer": "In the UK, the requirement for a license to fly a drone depends on the weight and purpose of the drone. If you are flying a drone for recreational purposes and it weighs less than 250 grams, you do not need a license. However, if you are flying a drone that weighs 250 grams or more, or if you are flying for commercial purposes, you may need to obtain the appropriate certification or permission. This could include registering your drone, obtaining a Flyer ID or Operator ID, or obtaining a PfCO or complying with the Open Category or Specific Category certifications. It is important to review the latest regulations and requirements from the CAA to determine if a license or certification is needed for your specific drone and purpose of use."
		}
	]
}
